<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Watching on Ronit Ray</title>
    <link>https://ronitray.xyz/watching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Watching on Ronit Ray</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020-22, Ronit Ray.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ronitray.xyz/watching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thor: Love and Thunder | (3/10)</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/watching/thor-love-and-thunder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/watching/thor-love-and-thunder/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, Marvel have released a LOT of pretty average to bad comics. It takes a good writer to be able to glean the best parts from these and ignore the cruft, and MCU writers have, for the most part, done great at this. It does take a truly incredible writer to take some of the best comics and produce something truly awful though, so congratulations to Taika Waititi for the absolute travesty that Love and Thunder is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars: Obi Wan Kenobi | (3/10)</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/watching/star-wars-obi-wan-kenobi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/watching/star-wars-obi-wan-kenobi/</guid>
      <description>An awful series with next to no redeeming features. Continues to reinforce the idea that Star Wars is spearheaded by morons whose idea of creativity is capitulating to whatever fans ask for.
&amp;ldquo;Fans&amp;rdquo;: I am fans. Me, a day before the first episode:
 I would watch this man watching paint dry tbh, so the mouse has got me good
 To be fair, Ewan was excellent throughout, and worth the price of admission alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness | (7/10)</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/watching/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/watching/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</guid>
      <description>Disney marketing is dumb as shit and they sold this giant Endgame level movie to everyone, only setting themselves up for disappointment. What we got instead is an (in my opinion), great story about three people, innocence lost in adversity, the things we do for love, how power changes you, who you are when you have power, and how far you would push the limits of your power when your back is against the wall, and the extent to which you hold true to your ideals when everyone questions them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
