<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Ronit Ray</title>
    <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Ronit Ray</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020-22, Ronit Ray.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ronitray.xyz/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stop Tinkering.</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/stop-tinkering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/stop-tinkering/</guid>
      <description>Tinkering is a trap, and I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen for it more times than I&amp;rsquo;m willing to admit.
It&amp;rsquo;s so much fun to play around with a new window manager on Linux and spend hours and hours &amp;ldquo;optimizing&amp;rdquo; the configuration for &amp;ldquo;maximum productivity&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;smoothest workflow&amp;rdquo;. Similarly, it&amp;rsquo;s also too easy to play around with your site&amp;rsquo;s CSS for hours and hours optimizing for some imaginary goal you&amp;rsquo;ll never reach. The problem, of course, is diminishing returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a reading log</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/reading-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/reading-log/</guid>
      <description>In an effort to push myself to keep writing, I&amp;rsquo;m going to steal an idea off the awesome Tom Macwright and start a reading log on this site. I had a goodreads account for a while, and quite enjoyed it, but I&amp;rsquo;m not quite fond of the UX of the site, and adding data to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s corpus isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly something that I&amp;rsquo;m dying to do. I deleted the account some time in 2019 or so, and don&amp;rsquo;t miss it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022: New systems, new learning, new site.</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/hello-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/hello-2022/</guid>
      <description>2021 ended on a whimper for me, with an incredibly stressful couple of months. While I am glad to be past that phase now, it is time for me to look forward and embrace the new year. Here&amp;rsquo;s some things I have planned.
Revamped habits I&amp;rsquo;ve been letting myself go the last couple of years, and it&amp;rsquo;s time I got myself back on track. I will be attempting to improve my systems this year and be more productive, more helpful, and more stable emotionally, mentally, and physically this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Feet (and mine) Wet in the World of Sports Analytics</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/sports-analytics-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/sports-analytics-starter/</guid>
      <description>Personal note: I love football. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get into the game very early in my life, but since age 12 or so, I have been absolutely obsessed. Earlier this year, I got a subscription to The Athleticand was exposed to some of the best football coverage I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. While I cannot afford the subscription anymore, I still have access to a lot of their content through podcasts and partner YouTube channels like the excellent Tifo Footballand Tifo IRL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn Substack articles into distraction-free blog posts in 60 seconds</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/clean-substack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/clean-substack/</guid>
      <description>Substack seems to be the new hotness for a variety of established as well as enthusiast writers and bloggers, and I understand the appeal. They seem to provide a fairly good monetization plan and have an easy enough process for even less technical people to get started.
I have no interest in moving to Substack and have not bothered creating an account either. My experience with the site comes from having authors&amp;rsquo; Substack links show up on HN or Reddit feeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recently- August 02-15</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/digest-aug2021-firsthalf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/digest-aug2021-firsthalf/</guid>
      <description>Of course I fall off a bandwagon the second after I start it. RIP Weekly Digests, here&amp;rsquo;s to more sporadic updates, I guess. Personally, things have not been great, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be writing about that. Here&amp;rsquo;s literally everything else that is keeping me sane.
Books I took some time off my read of Don Quixote to join a read-along of the Percy Jackson and the Olympians series with a group of friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix the Dock on PopOS for Productivity and Profit</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/popos-dock-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/popos-dock-changes/</guid>
      <description>After years on KDE and then a variety of minimal window managers, I installed System76&amp;rsquo;s PopOS on my personal laptop a few months ago. GNOME has, historically, really not been my thing, but I&amp;rsquo;ve come to really appreciate the way Pop does things.
In many ways Pop has provided a very sane, quick set of defaults that gets out of my way and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need me to tweak much to get started and go about my work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Digest: Jul 26 - Aug 01, 2021</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/digest-jul2021-week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/digest-jul2021-week4/</guid>
      <description>So my plan for this blog was to write (on average at least) one post a week for an entire year to just see if I could, and maybe to polish out my writing. We&amp;rsquo;re about 30 weeks into the year and I have only about 21 posts written, so it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that cat isn&amp;rsquo;t getting back in the bag anytime soon.
And so, for the purpose of stat-padding, or, in a more charitable sense, writing without much original thought, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of putting up a weekly &amp;ldquo;digest&amp;rdquo; of content I enjoyed across the internet and sporadically outside of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Sustainable Personal Wiki for Free</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/personal-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/personal-wiki/</guid>
      <description>Order is beautiful. My mind is an absolute mess, and the idea of offloading some of it into a structured place that I may never revisit, but can if I want to, is extremely appealing to me at the moment. I&amp;rsquo;ve also greatly been inspired by incredible public archives like Nikita Voloboev&amp;rsquo;s and Rasul Kireev&amp;rsquo;s. I think they&amp;rsquo;re incredible and would very much like to build a personal repository that will outlive me and might bring value to someone after I&amp;rsquo;m gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging StackOverflow for Productivity (and Profit?)</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/stackoverflow-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/stackoverflow-faster/</guid>
      <description>StackOverflow is a blessing. It&amp;rsquo;s a career maker and a career saver for almost every software engineer I know, myself included. That said, it can be better.
The vast majority of StackOverflow usage at work, at least for me, is looking for solutions that exist already. I don&amp;rsquo;t need the account features (it has been months since I&amp;rsquo;ve logged in). I land on the question&amp;rsquo;s page from my search engine, and bounce when I am done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lancelot- My Brainchild (a short story I wrote 10 years ago)</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/lancelot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/lancelot/</guid>
      <description>Quick note: While rummaging through some old boxes, I found a notebook from years ago. In it, among a host of other terrible essays, was this little short story that I had written when I was maybe 11 or 12 years old. I&amp;rsquo;m putting it up here as a bit of fun, and for archival purposes. I don&amp;rsquo;t even want to begin to get into the technical and factual inaccuracies or the ridiculous prose, but reader, if you find yourself wondering &amp;ldquo;what a fucking sociopath this kid is&amp;rdquo;, know that you&amp;rsquo;re not alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoatCounter- Simple, Tracking-Free Analytics</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/goatcounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/goatcounter/</guid>
      <description>I like the idea of analytics. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a bad thing to know which posts of yours are getting traction, what your readers would like to read, and so on. I am, however, staunchly pro-privacy. I will not stand for any analytics or telemetry:
 whose purpose goes beyond introspection which is used for collecting personally identifiable information which is used to profile users which is used to drive ad networks or sell collected data which is heavy and increases the size (and therefore the loading time) of a website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Build: COVID-19 Vaccination Tracker (for India)</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/covid-vaccine-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/covid-vaccine-tracker/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year. Birds are chirping, people are dying, your government has chosen to ignore a massive supply-side vaccine shortage, allowed manufacturers to set their own prices and opened up vaccine bookings for all citizens, thus shifting the onus to get vaccinated entirely upon you&amp;hellip; perfectly normal and rather wonderful.
The number of vaccines available in my city is extremely low at the moment. Hospitals declare stocks on the government portal as they please, and then it is pretty much a game of fastest finger first to grab a booking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t FLoC with my Heart</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/no-floc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/no-floc/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, Google launched an initiative called Federated Learning of Cohorts (FLoC for short) in their Chrome browser. The idea (or the marketing copy, anyway) is that FLoC will allow Google to serve you targeted ads without explicitly releasing identifying data or using third-party cookies. Every website you visit will be used by Google&amp;rsquo;s browser to train their classifiers and put you in buckets called cohorts, and members of each cohort can then be targeted based on their shared interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face-Eating Leopards and Humble Pie (Signal, why?)</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/signal-humble-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/signal-humble-pie/</guid>
      <description>All three (a very bold estimate, probably) of my readers will know that I have been a pretty outspoken advocate for Signal as a messaging app. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent quite a while waxing lyrical about its security and privacy benefits, and those points still stand pretty well. Unfortunately, Signal has decided to go and add some kind of altcoin nonsense to their app.
Read more about this:
 Help Us Test Payments in Signal: The official announcement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Use Units for Line Height (Txti Please!)</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/line-height-units-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/line-height-units-css/</guid>
      <description>Line height is an important CSS property. I feel like either I&amp;rsquo;m getting old or the system/browser default line height is just not good enough for most modern websites. When you&amp;rsquo;re reading large walls of text, single-line spacing can get pretty fatiguing quite fast. MDN specifically has an &amp;ldquo;Accessibility Concerns&amp;rdquo; section on its line-height documentation, stating:
 Use a minimum value of 1.5 for line-height for main paragraph content. This will help people experiencing low vision conditions, as well as people with cognitive concerns such as Dyslexia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp is Down</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/whatsapp-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/whatsapp-down/</guid>
      <description>Almost exactly two months ago, Signal went down.
In my post about it, I mentioned these were likely growing pains and the platform would get more stable as they learn to deal with the new scale of their user base and as donations and support come in to help them out. I also said:
 It is worth remembering that even services that are backed by some of the largest corporations in the world like WhatsApp have been down similarly less than a year ago, and have experienced scaling issues during the pandemic as more people find themselves online than ever before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Back Up Your Signal Conversations</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/signal-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/signal-backup/</guid>
      <description>Signal has established itself as one of the major encrypted messengers to stake a claim as a WhatsApp replacement of late. However, there are factors that affect usability negatively, many of which are deliberate decisions to favour privacy and security. One of these is the fact that no cloud backups are offered by the app. They want nothing to do with how you store your conversations, and would likely need a LOT more money if they had to store all your conversations themselves (a-la Telegram) or lose a lot of trust if they had to delegate the task to Google, Apple or some other provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Your Phone as a Webcam</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/droidcam-phone-webcam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/droidcam-phone-webcam/</guid>
      <description>I had an interview this week. Of course, the pandemic still looming over our heads meant that this was to be virtual rather than in-person. Videocalls are really not part of my workflow; I&amp;rsquo;m more of a text-oriented person. Even work-related discussion is usually limited to voice chat. The integrated webcam on my laptop was already pretty crummy, and five years of having tape on it probably didn&amp;rsquo;t do the quality any favours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Doing to Improve this Site&#39;s Accessibility</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/site-accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/site-accessibility/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve had on my mind from the very beginning for this site is accessibility. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect huge viewership now or ever, but making the content accessible to as many users as possible is something I greatly value and want to achieve. The internet wasn&amp;rsquo;t built for a handful of people who have perfect eyesight and gigabit internet, and I&amp;rsquo;m not going to let my site be reduced to that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Handle My Passwords</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/passwords-private/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/passwords-private/</guid>
      <description>This post comes in soon after LastPass announced that they are restructuring their free tier to only allow access from one category of devices, i.e. only desktops or only mobile devices. I assume this will be a no-go for many users, and given the high (~$36/year) subscription costs, several people will be unwilling to upgrade to their premium offering.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not using a password manager, you&amp;rsquo;re just asking for trouble, and/or putting in a lot of unnecessary effort memorizing several passwords when you could just remember one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecstatic v0.1 Documentation</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/ecstatic-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/ecstatic-documentation/</guid>
      <description>What is Ecstatic? Ecstatic is a static site generator. It is written in Python and makes use of, primarily, the Jinja template engine to generate a complete website. It is ideal for blogs and/or personal/company sites.
Installing Note: You need to have Python and git installed on your system to use ecstatic. It has been built using Python 3+, and not tested on 2.x. It may work, but please don&amp;rsquo;t expect support on deprecated versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecstatic v0.1 Release</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/ecstatic-v01-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/ecstatic-v01-release/</guid>
      <description>Today I am formally releasing v0.1 of Ecstatic, a static site generator that I wrote in Python using the Jinja template engine.
This generator was initially intended only to generate this blog, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to make it generic enough to be extensible.
 Source on GitHub Documentation  Please note that this is a point release and is still very much a minimal and raw project. I definitely recommend getting your hands dirty with it, but you should think twice before deploying it in a production environment where things move quickly and break fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art and Expectation</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/art-intentions-taylorswift-lovestory-fearless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/art-intentions-taylorswift-lovestory-fearless/</guid>
      <description>CW: mentions of suicide and mental health later in the article. Taylor Swift and I were both young when I first saw (and heard) her. I was 13, and she 21. Like many before me, my first exposure to her was her song &amp;ldquo;Love Story&amp;rdquo;, part of her second studio album titled &amp;lsquo;Fearless&amp;rsquo;. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot for me to be hooked; it was a really good song that spoke to my teen anxieties like few others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reclaim Control Over Your Content Consumption with RSS Feeds</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/use-rss-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/use-rss-feeds/</guid>
      <description>This is part 1 in a two-part series on RSS feeds.
The early internet was, I believe, truly ahead of its time. We have a lot more eye candy and fancy functionality today, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure, but some of the most enduring ideas at the foundation of the internet are just a little younger than the internet itself. One of these is the RSS feed. No matter what your site is, what content you post, or how it looks, an RSS feed is able to standardize its contents into a single XML file that can then be used to track updates, or what we have come to call &amp;ldquo;follow&amp;rdquo; you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography- A Regret and A Request</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/crypto-regret-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/crypto-regret-request/</guid>
      <description>In my second year in university as a CS major, I pitched an academic paper to an IEEE conference along with three colleagues. The paper highlighted a &amp;ldquo;novel&amp;rdquo; symmetric encryption scheme that we&amp;rsquo;d spent the better part of the summer brainstorming. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t without its merits, and seemed to fulfill the absolute basics of cryptography well enough. We mostly thought of it as a toy project, and went ahead to make an encrypted chat application, where keys were generated on the initiating device and shared to the recipient via an implementation of the Diffie-Hellman Key Exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal: Down, but Not Out</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/signal-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/signal-down/</guid>
      <description>Signal services were down at night (IST) on Friday, 15th January, 2021.
As of the time this article goes up, services remain suspended. People who have moved their entire, or a sizable portion of their networks over recently are grasping at ways to contact each other again, some falling back to greener pastures like WhatsApp, and others looking for alternatives already.
I&amp;rsquo;m not saying this is acceptable. I understand the criticality that often comes with instant messaging, and the problems that arise if networks suddenly collapse on you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Pages to Neocities, a New Home</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/gh-to-neocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/gh-to-neocities/</guid>
      <description>Today, I moved this website over from GitHub Pages to Neocities.
There&amp;rsquo;s not much to the decision, really. There are several hosting options for static sites like GH Pages, GitLab Pages, Netlify, and now even Cloudflare Pages. Anyone starting out should be more than fine picking any of these options. But here&amp;rsquo;s what drew me to Neocities.
When you use Neocities, it is extremely evident that they are a &amp;ldquo;little guy&amp;rdquo; company that puts its values up front for everyone to see, and backs them up by making the source freely available for anyone to audit and augment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don&#39;t Use Telegram</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/why-i-dont-use-telegram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/why-i-dont-use-telegram/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp recently rolled out changes to its privacy policy that highlight how user data is shared with Facebook in a common pool of data from all Facebook-owned services. While this just sheds light on practices that one must assume have been in play since WhatsApp was acquired by Facebook 6 years ago, putting it front and center seems to have been enough to give a not-insignificant portion of its user base a sense of unease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bucking Social Media Attraction with Light Frontends</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/alt-social-frontends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/alt-social-frontends/</guid>
      <description>My struggles with social media are long-standing and will likely wage on for years to come (separate post about that later perhaps). That said, I was looking for ways to minimize the time I spend on any social sites across all my devices. Unfortunately, my friends send me links to things on Reddit and Twitter that I am interested in or need to read to be part of the conversation, and there are other cases like checking the match thread on r/chelseafc when one of our matches is on that I like doing and want to continue doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Letting Go</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/on-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/on-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>The year was 2017. I was fresh off reading almost a hundred books in the previous year and raring to go again. My to-read lists on Goodreads and in notebooks and excel spreadsheets were overflowing with entries, most of them likely to be enjoyable. I was taking pride in being called &amp;ldquo;well-read&amp;rdquo; by peers, and just about beginning to feel the same way about myself. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy.
In hindsight, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to say I made a change in my life because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy, but the truth is I never know if I&amp;rsquo;m happy or not on a given day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Reinventing the Wheel</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/on-reinventing-the-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/on-reinventing-the-wheel/</guid>
      <description>On an interesting thread in HN today, there was much discussion on the idea of reinventing the wheel in software projects and writing one&amp;rsquo;s own static site generators. As someone fresh out of college where reinventing the wheel is not only encouraged but mandated in several areas to learn concepts, and also as someone who has &amp;ldquo;written&amp;rdquo; their own &amp;ldquo;static site generator&amp;rdquo;, I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s worth exploring this a little.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tags are a thing now, I guess</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/tags_now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/tags_now/</guid>
      <description>In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing my own static site generator in Python to generate this site. The initial codebase was borrowed with thanks from Naveera Ashraf&amp;rsquo;s very helpful blog post. I have since put in some of my own code to implement the following:
  A homepage template with some formatting to show a bio and some relevant links aside from the blog feed. This works pretty well as a homepage for a personal site and is extensible to include fancy CSS and JS if someone is so inclined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Note-Taking Applications</title>
      <link>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/notes-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronitray.xyz/writing/notes-workflow/</guid>
      <description>One of the books I&amp;rsquo;m reading this week, Make Time: How to Focus on what Matters Every Day by Jake Knapp and John Zeratsky, which is, by the way, the least self-helpy self-help book I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a while, maybe ever, had this passage that really resonated with me:
 I’ve been burned by fancy tools. Back in 2006, I discovered the perfect productivity software: a simple but powerful app called Mori that allowed for infinitely customizable note taking and filing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
