<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reading on Ronit Ray</title><link>https://ronitray.xyz/reading/</link><description>Recent content in Reading on Ronit Ray</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020-22, Ronit Ray.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ronitray.xyz/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Mixer: The Story of Premier League Tactics, from Route One to False Nines, by Michael Cox (4/5)</title><link>https://ronitray.xyz/reading/the-mixer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ronitray.xyz/reading/the-mixer/</guid><description>This is an awesome book! I have adored Michael Cox&amp;rsquo;s work for The Athletic for quite a while, and have heard nothing but praise for this book before going in. Happy to report all of it is quite justified- The Mixer is a great read.
The Premier League is the largest football league in the world, and has a very distinct identity. It is flashy, competitive, lucrative, and very influential. And yet, it is only 30 years old.</description></item><item><title>The House in the Cerulean Sea, by TJ Klune | (3/5)</title><link>https://ronitray.xyz/reading/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ronitray.xyz/reading/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/</guid><description>I received The House in the Cerulean Sea as a secret santa gift this festive season from someone very dear to me. I wanted to jump on it as soon as possible, and I did. It was pretty good.
This book isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly novel in concept. Uptight man who is extremely set in his ways one day embarks on an adventure that will change his life forever, bringing him a new outlook on life, new love, and a found family.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Habits, by James Clear | (3.75/5)</title><link>https://ronitray.xyz/reading/atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ronitray.xyz/reading/atomic-habits/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not fond of the self-help genre. It tends to be filled with terribly-written books by terrible people prescribing terrible advice. And while I&amp;rsquo;m aware that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of preconceived notions to bring to the table, it isn&amp;rsquo;t an opinion that I have arrived on lightly and it certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t an argument without merit. All that said, this was pretty good.
James Clear immediately stands out from the peddlers of bad self-help because he isn&amp;rsquo;t some rando off the street.</description></item></channel></rss>